A Guide to the Foundation for Child Development records FA019
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Annual Reports, 1898-1998; 2
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 48, Reel 33, Frame 474)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Reel 33, Frame 509, Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Reel 33, Frame 552, Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Reel 33, Frame 588, Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Reel 33, Frame 615, Box 2, Folder 51A)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Reel 33, Frame 638, Box 2, Frame 52)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Reel 33, Frame 677, Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Reel 33, Frame 710, Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 55, Reel 33, Frame 749)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Reel 33, Folder 785, Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 57, Reel 33, Frame 826)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 58, Reel 33, Frame 868)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 59, Reel 33, Frame 909)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 60, Reel 34, Frame 1)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 61, Reel 34, Frame 37)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Reel 34, Frame 75, Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1989-1990 (Reel 34, Frame 123, Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Reel 34, Folder 177, Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Reel 34, Frame 235, Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1992-1993 (Reel 34, Frame 291, Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1993-1994 (Reel 34, Frame 346, Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Reel 34, Frame 383, Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Reel 34, Frame 426, Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Reel 34, Frame 472, Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Foundation for Child Development - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Reel 34, Frame 515, Box 3, Folder 71)
- Financial Records, 1964-1992, 1996; 3
  This series is arranged in 2 subseries:
  Subseries 1 - Ledgers and Statements
  Subseries 2 - Meetings of the Finance Committee
  Appraisal
  - Ledgers and Statements, 1975-1984, 1988-1990; 1
    This subseries is arranged in 4 sub-subseries:
    Sub-subseries 1 - General Ledgers
    Sub-subseries 2 - Investment Portfolios
    Sub-subseries 3 - Statements
    Sub-subseries 4 - Tax Returns
    - General Ledgers, 1975-1984; 1
      - Series 3.1.1 - Financial Records - Ledgers and Statements - General Ledgers, 1975-1984 (Reel 34, Frame 573)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1975-March 31, 1976 (Reel 34, Frame 574)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1976-March 31, 1978 (Reel 34, Frame 665)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1978-March 31, 1979 (Reel 34, Frame 872)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1979-March 31, 1980 (Reel 35, Frame 1)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1980-March 31, 1981 (Reel 35, Frame 101)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1981-March 31, 1982 (Reel 35, Frame 215)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1982-March 31, 1983 (Reel 35, Frame 338)
      - General Ledgers, April 1, 1983-March 31, 1984 (Reel 35, Frame 458)
    - Investment Portfolios, 1980-1982, 1988-1990; 2
      - Series 3.1.2 - Financial Records - Ledgers and Statements - Investment Portfolios, 1980-1982, 1988-1990 (Reel 35, Frame 591)
      - Investment Portfolios, November-December 1980 (Reel 35, Frame 593)
      - Investment Portfolios, January-March 1981 (Reel 35, Frame 612)
      - Investment Portfolios, April-June 1981 (Reel 35, Frame 655)
      - Investment Portfolios, July-September 1981 (Reel 35, Frame 683)
      - Investment Portfolios, October-December 1981 (Reel 35, Frame 716)
      - Investment Portfolios, January-March 1982 (Reel 35, Frame 744)
      - Investment Portfolios, April-June 1988 (Reel 35, Frame 770)
      - Investment Portfolios, July-September 1988 (Reel 35, Frame 801)
      - Investment Portfolios, October-December 1988 (Reel 35, Frame 843)
      - Investment Portfolios, January-March 1989 (Reel 35, Frame 883)
      - Investment Portfolios, April-June 1989 (Reel 35, Frame 908)
      - Investment Portfolios, July-September 1989 (Reel 35, Frame 933)
      - Investment Portfolios, October-December 1989 (Reel 35, Frame 959)
      - Investment Portfolios, January-March 1990 (Reel 36, Frame 1)
    - Statements, 1988-1989; 3
      - Series 3.1.3 - Financial Records - Ledgers and Statements - Statements, 1988-1989 (Reel 36, Frame 4)
      - Financial Statements, 1988 (Reel 36, Frame 25)
      - Financial Statements, 1989 (Reel 36, Frame 74)
    - Tax Returns, 1968-1977; 4
      - Series 3.1.4 - Financial Records - Ledgers and Statements - Tax Returns, 1968-1977 (Reel 36, Frame 116)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1970-March 31, 1971, 1970-1971 (Reel 36, Frame 117)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1971-March 31, 1972 (Reel 36, Frame 172)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1972-March 31, 1973 (Reel 36, Frame 309)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1973-March 31, 1974 (Reel 36, Frame 402)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1973-March 31, 1974 (Reel 36, Frame 431)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1974-March 31, 1975 (Reel 36, Frame 567)
      - Federal Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1975-March 31, 1976 (Reel 36, Frame 713)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1968-March 31, 1969 (Reel 36, Frame 891)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1969-March 31, 1970 (Reel 36, Frame 929)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1970-March 31, 1971 (Reel 36, Frame 996)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1971-March 31, 1972 (Reel 36, Frame 1037)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1972-March 31, 1973 (Reel 37, Frame 1)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1973-March 31, 1974 (Reel 37, Frame 112)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1974-March 31, 1975 (Reel 37, Frame 230)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1975-March 31, 1976 (Reel 37, Frame 349)
      - New York State Tax Returns - Fiscal Year April 1, 1976-March 31, 1977 (Reel 37, Frame 451)
  - Meetings of the Finance Committee, 1964-1996; 2
    Actual dates for this Subseries are 1964-1967, 1969, 1971-1976, 1978-1983, 1986-1992, 1996.
    - Series 3.2 - Financial Records - Meetings of the Finance Committee, 1964-1967, 1969, 1971-1976, 1978-1983, 1986-1992, 1996 (Reel 37, Frame 517)
    - July 28, 1964 (Reel 37, Frame 518)
    - May 7, 1965 (Reel 37, Frame 520)
    - October 4, 1966 (Reel 37, Frame 525)
    - November 2, 1966 (Reel 37, Frame 554)
    - June 30, 1967 (Reel 37, Frame 560)
    - November 3, 1967 (Reel 37, Frame 579)
    - June 25, 1969 (Reel 37, Frame 585)
    - May 20, 1971 (Reel 37, Frame 614)
    - October 29, 1971 (Reel 37, Frame 671)
    - March 21, 1972 (Reel 37, Frame 769)
    - September 20, 1973 (Reel 37, Frame 812)
    - June 11, 1974 (Reel 37, Frame 907)
    - July 23, 1974 (Reel 37, Frame 950)
    - October 24, 1974 (Reel 37, Frame 1029)
    - February 20, 1975 (Reel 37, Frame 1053)
    - September 3, 1975 (Reel 37, Frame 1067)
    - March 1, 1976 (Reel 38, Frame 1)
    - October 28, 1976 (Reel 38, Frame 48)
    - November 14, 1978 (Reel 38, Frame 110)
    - February 20, 1979 (Reel 38, Frame 154)
    - May 15, 1979 (Reel 38, Frame 271)
    - September 12, 1979 (Reel 38, Frame 303)
    - December 6, 1979 (Reel 38, Frame 305)
    - June 11, 1980 (Reel 38, Frame 356)
    - July 15, 1980 (Reel 38, Frame 412)
    - July 30, 1980 (Reel 38, Frame 422)
    - November 3, 1980 (Reel 38, Frame 435)
    - January 16, 1981 (Reel 38, Frame 467)
    - May 22, 1981 (Reel 38, Frame 562)
    - September 11, 1981 (Reel 38, Frame 659)
    - November 24, 1981 (Reel 38, Frame 776)
    - February 23, 1982 (Reel 38, Frame 860)
    - May 24, 1982 (Reel 38, Frame 976)
    - September 14, 1982 (Reel 38, Frame 1100)
    - November 23, 1982 (Reel 39, Frame 1)
    - February 14, 1983 (Reel 39, Frame 57)
    - May 31, 1983 (Reel 39, Frame 136)
    - December 5, 1983 (Reel 39, Frame 205)
    - May 19, 1986 (Reel 39, Frame 209)
    - September 22, 1986 (Reel 39, Frame 212)
    - November 26, 1986 (Reel 39, Frame 229)
    - December 1, 1987 (Reel 39, Frame 234)
    - September 8, 1987 (Reel 39, Frame 319)
    - February 23, 1988 (Reel 39, Frame 331)
    - June 6, 1988 (Reel 39, Frame 421)
    - September 14, 1988 (Reel 39, Frame 465)
    - November 28, 1988 (Reel 39, Frame 484)
    - February 28, 1989 (Reel 39, Frame 580)
    - June 6, 1989 (Reel 39, Frame 627)
    - June 4, 1990 (Reel 39, Frame 660)
    - September 25, 1990 (Reel 39, Frame 689)
    - December 4, 1990 (Reel 39, Frame 756)
    - March 5, 1991 (Reel 39, Frame 799)
    - June 11, 1991 (Reel 39, Frame 857)
    - September 24, 1991 (Reel 39, Frame 899)
    - December 2, 1991 (Reel 39, Frame 951)
    - March 3, 1992 (Reel 39, Frame 956)
    - June 2, 1992 (Reel 39, Frame 1051)
    - November 12, 1992 (Reel 39, Frame 1119)
    - February 6, 1996 (Reel 39, Frame 1125)
    - May 7, 1996 (Reel 40, Frame 1)
    - August 6, 1996 (Reel 40, Frame 40)
    - November 6, 1996 (Reel 40, Frame 91)
  - Reprints, 1954-1974; 5
    Reprints are arranged alphabetically by the author's last name. When there are multiple authors, an asterisk immediately follows the grantee-author's name, and the reprint is filed alphabetically according to this name. Additional pamphlets concerning seminar proceedings and related scientific studies follow this alphabetical sequence. Pamphlets published by the Foundation for Child Development may also be listed under the Foundation's former name, the Association for the Aid of Crippled Children (AACC).
    This series contains scientific papers and pamphlets authored by grantees, officers, and consultants of the Foundation for Child Development. These materials have been retained in their original form and have not been microfilmed.
    - Reprints (A) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Abramson, Harold. "History of the Special Committee on Infant Mortality: A Blueprint of Planned Programs for Postgraduate Medical Education." "New York Medicine 27," no. 8, (August 1971): 298-303.
      Abramson, Harold. "History of the Special Committee on Infant Mortality: A Blueprint of Planned Programs for Postgraduate Medical Education." "New York Medicine 27," no. 7, (July 1971): 272-280.
    - Reprints (B) (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Baumgartner, Leona and Jean Pakter, M.D. "Assessing the Local Situation, in The Challenge of Fetal Loss, Prematurity and Infant Mortality," in "The Challenge of Fetal Loss, Prematurity, and Infant Mortality." Paper presented at the annual meeting of the Association for the Aid of Crippled Children, New York, New York, 1956.
      Beck, Bertram M. "The Lower East Side Family Union: A Social Invention." An Occasional Paper from the Foundation for Child Development, New York, New York, March 1979.
      Belmont, Ira. "The Relation of Afferent Changes to Motor Performance in the Rehabilitation of Cerebrally Damaged Patients." "Bulletin of The New York Academy of Medicine" 42, no. 10, (October 1966): 918-922.
      Berg, Alan. "Famine Contained: Notes and LEssons from the Bilhar Experience." "Famine: A Symposium Dealing with Nutrition and Relief Operations in Times of Disaster," Swedish Nutrition Foundation and the Swedish International Development Authority (SIDA) (ed.), The Swedish Nutrition Foundation, 1971. Reprint #211, Washington, D. C., The Brookings Institution, 1971.
      Berg, Alan. "Industry's Struggle with World Malnutrition." "Harvard Business Review" (January-February 1972). Reprint #232, Washington, D. C., The Brookings Institution.
      Berg, Alan D. "Nutrition as a National Priority: Lessons from the India Experiment." "The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition" 23, no. 1, (November 1970). Reprint #90, Washington, D. C., The Brookings Institution, March 1971.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Lillian Belmont. "Auditory-Visual Integration, Intelligence and Reading Ability in School Children." "Perceptual and Motor Skills" 20 (1965): 295-305.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Lillian Belmont. "Auditory-Visual Integration in Normal and Retarded Readers." "The American Journal of Orthopsychiatry" 24, no. 5 (October 1964): 852-861.
      Belmont, Lillian, Birch, Herbert G.* and Ira Belmont. "Auditory-Visual Intersensory Processing and Verbal Mediation." "The Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease" 147, no. 6 (1968): 562-569.
      Birch, Herbert G., Thomas, Alexander, and Stella Chess. "Behavioral Development in Brain-Damaged Children: Three Case Studies." "Archives of General Psychiatry" 2, (December 1964): 596-603.
      Chess, Stella, Thomas, Alexander and Herber G. Birch*. "Characteristics of the Individual Child's Behavioral Responses to the Environment." "American Journal of Orthopsychiatry" 29, no. 4 (October 1959).
    - Reprints (B) (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Birch, Herbert G. and Lillian Belmont. "Development and Disturbance in Auditory-Visual Integration." "E.E.N.T. Digest" 28, (December 1966): 47-63.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Jack Tizard. "The Dietary Treatment of Phenylketonuria: Not Proven?" "Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology" 9, no. 1, (February 1967): 9-12.
      Cravioto, J., Birch, H. G.*, De Licardie, E., Rosales, L. and L. Vega. "The Ecology of Growth and Development in a Mexican Preindustrial Community Report 1: Methods and Findings from Birth to One Month of Age." "Society for Research in Child Development," Serial No. 129, Volume 34, no. 5.
      Cravioto, Joaquin, Birch, Herbert G.*, De Licardie, Elsa R. and Lydia Rosales. "The Ecology of Infant Weight Gain in a Pre-industrial Society." "Acta Paediatrica Scndinavica" 56 (January 1967): 71-84.
      Turkewitz, Gerald, Herbert G. Birch*, Tina Moreau, Linda Levy and Anne C. Cornwell. "Effect of Intensity of Auditory Stimulation on Directional Eye Movements in the Human Neonate." "Animal Behavior" 14 (1966): 93-101.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Howard Demb. "The Formation and Extinction of Conditioned Reflexes in 'Brain-Damaged' and Mongoloid Children." "The Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease" 129, no. 2, (August 1959): 162-170.
      Klapper, Zelda S. and Herbert G. Birch*. "A Fourteen-Year Follow-Up Study of Cerebral Palsy: Intellectual Change and Stability." "American Journal of Orthopsychiatry" 37, no. 3 (April 1967): 540-547.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Stephen A. Richardson. "The Functioning Jamaican School Children Severely Malnourished During the First Two Years of Life." "Nutrition, The Nervous System, and Behavior," Scientific Publication 251, Pan American Health Organization.
      Rutter, Michael, Korn, Sam and Herbert G. Birch*. "Genetic and Environmental Factors in the Development of Primary Reaction Patterns." "British Journal of Social Clinical Psychology" 2 (1963): 161-173.
      Turkewitz, Gerald, Moreau, Tina and Herbert G. Birch*. "Head Position and Receptor Organization in the Human Neonate." "Journal of Experimental Child Psychology" 4, no. 2 (October 1966): 169-177.
      Turkewitz, Gerald, Gordon, Edmund W. and Herbert G. Birch*. "Head Turning in the Human Neonate: Effect of Prandial Condition and Lateral Preference." "Journal of Comparative and Physiological Psychology" 59, no. 2, (1965): 189-192.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Arthur Lefford. "Intersensory Development in Children." "The Society of Research in Child Development" 28, no. 5, Serial No. 89, Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Development, 1963.
      Rutter, Michael, Graham, Philip and Herbert G. Birch*. "Interrelations Between the Choreiform Syndrome, Reading Disability and Psychiatric Disorder in Children 8-11 Years." "Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology" 8, no. 2 (April 1966): 149-159.
      Belmont, Lillian and Herbert G. Birch*. "Lateral Dominance and Right-LEft Awareness in Normal Children." "Child Development" 34 (1963): 257-270.
    - Reprints (B) (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Hertzig, Margaret E., Bortner, Morton and Herbert G. Birch*. "Neurologic Findings in Children Educationally Designated as "Brain-Damaged"." "American Journal of Orthopsychiatry" 39, no. 3 (April 1969).
      Hertzig, Margaret E. and Herbert G. Birch*. "Neurologic Organization in Psychiatrically Disturbed Adolescents: A Comparative Consideration of Sex Differences." "Archives of General Psychiatry" 19 (November 1968): 528-537.
      Hertzig, Margaret E. and Herbert G. Birch*. "Neurologic Organization in psychiatrically Disturbed Adolescent Girls." "Archives of General Psychiatry" 15 (December 1966): 590-598.
      Cravioto, Joaquin, De Licardie, Elsa R. and Herbert G. Birch*. "Nutrition, Grown and Neurointegrative Development: An Experimental and Ecologic Study." "Pediatrics" 38, no. 2, Part II, (August 1966): 319-37.
      Birch, Herbert G., Proctor, Florry and Morton Bortner. "Perception in Hemiplegia. IV: Body Surface Localization in Hemiplegic Patients." "The Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease" 133, no. 3 (September 1961): 192-202.
      Belmont, Ira and Herbert G. Birch*. "Perceptual Evidence of CNS Dysfunction in Schizophrenia." "Archives of General Psychiatry" 10 (April 1964): 395-408.
      Belmont, Lillian and Herbert G. Birch*. "The Intellectual Profile of Retarded Readers." "Perceptual and Motor Skills" 22 (1966): 787-816. Southern Universities Press, Albert Einstein College of Medicine of Yeshiva University, Monograph Supplement 6-V22, 1966.
      Bortner, Morton and Herbert G. Birch*. "Perceptual and Perceptual-Motor Dissociation in Brain-Damaged Patients." "The Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease" 130, no. 1 (January 1960): 49-53.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Harry A. Walker. "Perceptual and Perceptual-Motor Dissociation, from Studies in Schizophrenic and Brain-Damaged Psychotic Children." "Studies of General Psychiatry" 14 (February 1966): 113-118.
      Klapper, Zelda S. and Herbert G. Birch*. "The Relation of Childhood Characteristics to Outcome in Young Adults with Cerebral Palsy." "Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology" 4, no. 8, (December 1966): 645-656.
      Birch, Herbert G., Belmont, Ira and Eric Karp. "The Relation of Single Stimulus Threshold to Extinction in Double Simultaneous Stimulation." "Cortex" 1 (1964): 19-39.
      Turkiwitz, Gerald, Fleischer, Susan, Moreau, Tina, Birch, Herbert G.* and Linda Levy. "Relationship Between Feeding Condition and Organization of Flexor-Extensor Movements in the Human Neonate." "Journal of Comparative and Physiological Psychology" 61, no. 3 (1966): 461-463.
      Birch, Herbert G., Belmont, Ira and Eric Karp. "Social Differences in Auditory Perception." "Perceptual and Motor Skills" 20 (1965): 861-870.
      Birch, Herbert G. and Morton Bortner. "Stimulus Competition and Category Usage in Normal Children." "The Journal of Genetic Psychology" 109 (1966): 195-204.
      Richardson, S. A., Birch, H. G.*, Grabie, E. and K. Yoder. "The Behavior of Children in School Who Were Severely Malnourished in the First Two Years of Life." "Journal of Health & Social Behavior" 13 (September 1972): 276-284.
      Belmont, Ira, Birch, Herbert G.* and Eric Karp. "The Sequence of Errors Made to Double Simultaneous Stimulation in Older Persons." "Cortex" 4 (1968): 280-287.
      Bonmassar, E., Bonmassar, A., Vadlamudi, S. and A. Goldin. "Immunological Alteration of Leukemic Cells 'In Vivo' after Treatment with an Antitumor Drug." "Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences" 66, no. 4 (August 1970): 1089-1095.
      Bonmassar, E., Cudkowica, G., Vadlamudi, S. and A. Goldin. "Influence of Tumor-Host Differences at a Single Histocompatibility Locus (H-1) on the Antileukemic Effect of 1,3-Bis (2-chloroethyl)-1-nitrosourea (NSC 409962)." "Cancer Research" 30, (October 1970): 2538-2542.
      Boy Scouts of America, "Scouting for the Physically Handicapped." "Boy Scouts of America" no. 3039, 1971.
    - Reprints (C) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Chernay, Patrice R., Hsu, Lillian Y. F., Streicher, H. and K. Hirschhorn. "Human Chromosome Identification by Differential Staining: G Group (21-22-Y)." "Cytogenetics" 10 (1971): 19-224.
      Clapp, James F. III, Abrams, Robert M., Caton, Donald, Cotter, Julian R. and Donald H. Barron. "The Oxygen Consumption of the Uterus and its Tissue Contents in Late Gestation: A Comparison of Simultaneous Measurements Using Two Different Techniques." "Quarterly Journal of Experimental Physiology" 57 (1972): 24-29.
    - Reprints (D-E) (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Davis, Fred. "Deviance Disavowal: The Management of Strained Interaction by the Visibly Handicapped." "Social Problems" 9, no. 2 (Fall 1961).
      Doxiadis, Spyros. "Babies Centre 'Metera." "Abbottempo." Book 2, Abbott Universal Ltd., (1968): 24-27.
      Dumpson, James R. "Public Welfare and Implementation of the 1967 Social Security Amendments." "Child Welfare" 47, no. 7 (July 1968).
      Eliot, Martha M. "The National Score," in "The Challenge of Fetal Loss, Prematurity, and Infant Mortality." Paper presented at the annual meeting of the Association for the Aid of Crippled Children, New York, New York, 1956. (see section 'B', Baumgartner)
    - Reprints (F) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Finch, Stuart M. and John H. Hess. "Ulcerative Colitis in Children." "The American Journal of Psychiatry" 118, no. 9 (March 1962).
      Frank, Charles W., Weinblatt, Eve, Shapiro, Sam, Seiden, George E. and Robert V. Sager. "The H.I.P. Study of Incidence and Prognosis of Coronary Heart Disease: Criteria for Diagnosis." "Journal of Chronic Diseases" 16 (1968): 1293-1312.
      Rivers, Thomas M., Warkany, Josef, Fraser, F. C.*, Wilson, James G., Matson, Donald D., McIntosh, Rustin. "Causes of Congenital Malformations in Human Beings." "Journal of Chronic Diseases" 10, no. 2 (August 1959): 83-151.
    - Reprints (G) (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Ginzberg, Eli. "Urban Health Services: The Case of New York." "Bulletin of The New York Academy of Medicine" Second Series 47, no. 4, (April 1971): 358-410.
      Grossi-Paoletti, E., P. Paoletti, Schiffer, D. and A. Fabiani. "Experimental Brain Tumours induced in Rats by Nitrosourea Derivatives, Part 2, Morphological Aspects of Nitrosoethylurea Tumours obtained by Transplacental Induction." "Journal of the Neurological Sciences" 11 (1970): 573-581.
      Weiss, J. F., E. Grossi-Paoletti*, P. Paoletti, Schiffer, D. and A. Fabiani. "Occurrence of Desmosterol in Tumors of the Nervous System Induced in the Rat by Nitrosourea Derivatives." "Cancer Research" 30 (August 1970): 2107-2109.
      Grossi-Paoletti, Enrica. "Tumori Cerebrali Sperimentali Indotti da Azopcomposti." "Archivo Italiano di Patologia e Clinica dei Tumori" Fasc. 1-2, 13 (1970): 3-23.
      Gruenberg, Ernest M. "The Epidemiology of Schizophrenia," vol. 2, of "American Handbook of Psychiatry," Second Edition, Child Adolescent Psychiatry, Sociocultural and Community Psychiatry. (Basic Books, 1974), 448-463.
      Gruenberg, Ernest M. "Progress in Psychiatric Epidemiology." "The Psychiatric Quarterly" 47, no. 1 (1973): 1-11.